Masquerades of Research: Part I is a drama film directed by Padraig Robinson.
A dialogic character study exploring the broader social impetus of Laud
Humphreys’ infamous 1968 dissertation in Sociology, Tearoom Trade.
The study was based on observations made in public restrooms in St.
Louis, colloquially called "tearooms", where homosexual men of
different socioeconomic classes engaged in sexual contact.
With his controversial research methods, in which he observed sexual acts as a voyeur, or so-called watchqueen,
and conducted interviews, Humphreys deliberately broke with the ethical protocols of science.
The film explores Humphrey’s intentions and the context of his research as well as the
personal and professional impact of the study on Humphrey’s career.
Vampire: The Masquerade – Bloodlines 2 is a 2025 action role-playing video game developed by
The Chinese Room and published by Paradox Interactive and White Wolf Publishing.
A sequel to Vampire: The Masquerade – Bloodlines (2004), it is set in the World of Darkness and follows an original narrative
focused on the Elder vampire Phyre, who awakens in early 21st-century Seattle during a historic snowstorm.
As the city's Camarilla struggles in the aftermath of a failed coup and a renewed inquisition, Phyre becomes entangled in the conflict between
factions of vampires, hunters, and the resurgent Sabbat while uncovering the truth behind a mysterious brand suppressing their powers.
Players control Phyre primarily from a first-person perspective, exploring an
open-world depiction of Seattle divided into five districts.
The game emphasizes traversal, investigation, dialogue, and supernatural combat,
allowing players to customize Phyre's clan, abilities, outfits, and backstory.
Feeding on humans replenishes blood used to power Disciplines (supernatural powers), while stealth,
persuasion, and manipulation can shape relationships with characters and factions.
Development of Bloodlines 2 began under Hardsuit Labs in the mid-2010s before successive
delays and production issues resulted in a shift to The Chinese Room in 2021.
The Chinese Room retained the Christmas-time Seattle setting and much of the original art direction but
rebuilt the game with a revised RPG system and narrative, while experiencing further delays.
Vampire: The Masquerade – Bloodlines 2 was released for PlayStation
5, Windows, and Xbox Series X/S on 21 October 2025.
The game received mixed critical reviews, drawing praise for its
narrative, and criticism for the gameplay and design.
It also failed to meet the studio's sales targets,
resulting in significant financial loss.